César Represa Bautista

Summary

I am a Computer Engineer with 4 years developing Web based enterprise applications with a special interest in server side services, using different libraries, frameworks and technologies. During this time, I also got experience working with payment systems and 3rd party services.

Aside from that, I'm interested in embedded systems, machine learning and cloud infrastructure. I like to invest time learning them doing side projects or attending to hackathons or meetups.

Experience

Backend developer, Plek - Amsterdam - 01/2017 to 01/2020

- Design and implementation of new features and support of the platform from server configuration until deployment and integration of new logic.
 Worked in the migration of the monolithic core of the app to microservices using the NestJS framework.
- Experience with payment provider systems like GlobalCollect and 3rd party services and integrations.
- Maintainer of the desktop native app base on Electron. I developed a system to release new updates of the app automatically when they're published on the website.

Backend developer, Ilumy - Amsterdam - 01/2017 to 01/2020

- My role was the setup, configuration and maintenance of the websites. Focused on Drupal websites and Typescript projects.
- In charge of the logic design and structure of the project to the deployment of a release to production.
- Developed and worked with different technologies like WebSockets, ElasticSearch or Redis.

Analyst programmer, Sugerendo Sistemas - Madrid - 01/2017 to 08/2017 (Reference letter)

- The main function was to give support to projects with E-commerce that required a certain technical solution.
- Development of new modules and functionalities to add to the online commerce of each client.
- Maintenance and management of online stores, from the server set to the optimum configuration of the administrator control panel.

Education

- Computer Engineer Degree, UPSAM, Madrid (España), Sep 2012 Jun 2016
- Aeronautical and Airport Management Certificate, Universidad San Pablo CEU, Madrid (España), Sep 2010 - Jun 2012
- High School, IES Astorga, Astorga (España), Sep 2004 Jul 2010



Contact

+31 684983437

contact@cesarb.dev

portfolio.cesarb.dev

linkedin.com/césar-represa-bautista

GitLab @cesarb1392

Languages

- Javascript
- Java
- PHP
- C / C++

Databases

- MongoDB
- MySQL / SQL / MariaDB
- PL/SQL

Technologies

- Docker
- Typescript
- Nginx & Apache
- ElasticSearch
- Redis
- Electron
- React, Angular
- Drupal, Magento

Technical Skills

- TDD, Mocha, Istanbul, Chai
- CI/CD, GIT, Jenkins
- Linux
- AWS